Charles Arbor?
That's who Professor Celia is marrying?
Well, it is your quintessential
marriage of convenience.
By which you mean...
In the last conflict,
the Kingdom of Beltrum suffered a
crushing defeat by the Proxia Empire.
Thanks to the actions of
the House of Duke Arbor,
we just barely managed to
commence negotiations for peace,
but the power and authority
of the royal family was lost.
When Duke Huguenot's faction was
made to take responsibility,
they fled the royal capital.
The House of Duke Arbor has
rallied their momentum,
and what they have chosen in
order to once more gain strength
is the House of Count Claire.
Does Professor Celia... no, does the House of
Count Claire desire this political marriage?
I don't know.
I don't have such detailed information.
What will you do, Haruto?
The wedding ceremony is tomorrow.
Before it happens, I want to see
Professor Celia and ask her in person.
Yes.
But the professor is in the castle.
Their defenses will be even
tighter than the Academy.
Then I'll use my spirit form and investigate.
A spirit in spirit form is
a mass of od and mana...
Something inside the castle may be set
to detect suspicious magical power.
Will you be all right?
I can visually perceive barriers
that are made to detect magic.
I see.
O-Oh, but Aishia, you and
the professor haven't—
I know what Celia looks like.
I'm counting on you, then.
Yes, leave it to me.
Seirei Gensouki
Silver Bride
I'm so sorry, Celia.
I just haven't been able to come to see you.
And now... it's already the
night before the wedding.
It couldn't be helped, Father.
You're busy with official matters.
Count Claire...
No, I suppose I should be calling
you "Father" now, shouldn't I?
The preparations for the ceremony
are complete. Please set your mind at ease.
I heard that the ceremony
will be a large event.
Yes.
This is a wedding between
our House of Duke Arbor
and the House of Count Claire, after all.
We'll be able to show those
inside and outside the kingdom
that the power of the
Kingdom of Beltrum is solid.
That said,
the state of affairs within the
kingdom is still disordered.
Security will be flawless, I expect?
Of course!
The Knights of the Royal Guard,
the Mage Corps, and others...
I've gathered our kingdom's very best.
Then I do feel more at ease. However...
I suppose worrying about everything
is part of parental love.
Thank you, Father.
Instead of you worrying for us,
Father, we are worried about you!
For some time, strange rumors
have been flowing from the royal court.
That you and a portion of the nobles
have been secretly in contact with
Duke Huguenot, who fled the kingdom.
That slander is completely unfounded.
Yes, I know.
But it is true that trust
in you has been shaken.
I would never betray this kingdom.
Father, please don't worry.
My marriage to Celia is partly
to help protect your standing.
The House of Duke Arbor would never
abandon the House of Count Claire.
And I am very grateful for that.
Father, soon we'll have
you serve as commander and director
of the House of Duke Arbor.
That's all right with you, isn't it?
That sounds like a threat...
My dear Celia, I am truly sorry.
If I were better at maneuvering...
I understand. I will do everything in
my power to fulfill this responsibility.
Well, then! To the peace and
prosperity of both our houses!
And to this beautiful bride.
To the both of you.
We are in your care, Lord Charles.
Father and I will both dedicate
ourselves entirely to this.
No, it is I who am grateful to you.
I look forward to the
wedding ceremony tomorrow.
Yes.
The defenses are very strong,
just as I thought.
Perhaps it's in preparation for tomorrow.
Haruto, I've found where Celia is.
Good. Where is she?
She's outside the palace.
Start at the main gate. On the left,
a fair ways in, there's a large building.
Understood. I'll head there now.
It's been such a long time
since I've seen Father,
but we weren't able to speak
as parent and child at all.
Still, with this, Father and the
House of Claire will be all right.
All that's left...
is for me to become that man's
property for the rest of my life.
Here at the very end...
I wish I could have seen him again.
For certain, absolutely certain, understand?
Stay safe...
until you return, all right?
I think probably...
the feelings I have for Rio are...
Who's there?
Quiet.
It's me, Professor Celia.
Rio.
What?
Oh.
It's been a long time.
R-Rio?
Yes.
Is it really you, Rio?
I've returned, just as I promised.
Though it's taken me four years to do it.
Rio!
It is you.
P-Professor...
Yes...
You're really here. It isn't a dream.
Professor, I've missed you.
Yes, as I have you!
All this time...
Yes.
Rio...
You've gotten quite a bit taller.
You haven't changed very
much at all, Professor.
I-I've grown a little more womanly!
Yes.
You have always been beautiful,
but you've grown even more lovely.
There you go, saying things
like that again!
You've grown dashing, Rio.
Strong and gallant.
Thank you very much.
I-I'm so glad you came back safe and sound.
Wait...
How did you get here?
You couldn't have snuck in, could you?
Yes, well...
Oh, right! Did you make it to the
Yagumo region? Where else did you go?
I want to hear everything!
Y-Yes...
Oh, wait.
Would you like some tea? Let's have some.
We often had tea together,
just the two of us, didn't we?
Yes, we did.
Since then, I've always
had tea alone, you know?
Professor... You're getting
married, aren't you?
I've heard that your groom is Charles Arbor.
Y-Yes.
That's right.
I know it's rude to ask so suddenly, but...
Is this wedding something
you want, Professor?
I am sorry to ask something like this.
But when I heard that the
wedding ceremony is tomorrow...
This wedding is something
I have agreed to, of course.
Even though the person
you're marrying... is Charles Arbor?
He's someone you have an ill-fated
connection with, isn't he?
I thought perhaps
this might have something to do with
the circumstances of your family.
No. I am of age, after all.
I can't think only of my research forever.
Really?
Yes!
And in spite of appearances, Lord Charles
is chivalrous and kind toward women!
Professor...
Then, will you marry me instead, Rio?
Or will you take me somewhere and
live the rest of your life with me?
I... uh...
Just kidding.
What?
I'm sorry. Please forget all of that.
Professor...
Rio, you should leave.
We haven't finished talking yet.
You can't stay. The people who
look after me will be here soon.
I have an early day tomorrow,
and there are a lot of preparations left.
I'm glad I was able to see
you before the ceremony.
Oh...
And don't come to the ceremony.
It's too embarrassing.
Now, then, hurry up and go.
Be careful not to get caught as you leave.
I'll close that door and give
you twenty seconds to go.
Go on.
If you don't hurry up and leave, I'll scream.
Come on!
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Thank you, Rio...
for coming back, just as you promised.
It made me truly happy.
But I can't let you get caught up in this.
Bye-bye, Rio.
Haruto?
I wasn't able to find out her true feelings.
What will you do?
I don't know.
But I want to know a little more
about what's motivating this wedding.
I will help you.
Sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
Because all I do is have you help me, Aishia.
I believe I've told you. I will
always be at your side, Haruto.
If you need me, you can come to me any time.
Thank you.
Fall in!
Sir!
Right face!
Lord Charles, I have brought Sir Reiss.
Ah!
Sir Reiss!
Allow me to offer congratulations
on this, the event of your wedding.
Thank you so much for coming!
With our relationship?
I am delighted to attend.
Yes, thank you!
When did you arrive in our royal capital?
I've just arrived.
If I'd known earlier that you'd be staying,
I'd have provided a proper welcome!
No, please don't trouble yourself.
Though we are officially at peace
with the Kingdom of Beltrum,
we two are from enemy countries.
If you are too friendly with me, I am sure
there are some who would not be amused.
I see.
So this time, I will keep my visit quiet.
I am touched by your consideration.
It's fine.
But once the ceremony is over,
please come to my home!
Tonight is your first night together.
I will visit another day.
Oh, well, I...
To take such trouble and to be
so considerate is quite, well...
I sense a spirit.
It's quite a powerful one.
Sir Reiss...
Is something wrong?
No, nothing.
I will go to the ceremony hall
early and wait there.
Allow me to send someone
to show you the way.
You there! Show Sir Reiss to the ceremony hall.
I am honored.
Sir!
Be sure to show him every courtesy.
It's disappeared.
Yes, sir.
Everything is fine.
I am a doll.
I have no feelings. I am just a doll.
Celia...
Please come out here a moment.
Yes, I'll be right out!
Oh, my...
You look m-magnificent, Celia! Truly beautiful!
Thank you very much, Lord Charles.
Very nice... Truly wonderful!
Even better than I'd imagined!
Are you nervous?
Don't worry. I am here.
Yes.
And, you see, I thought it might
help you feel more relaxed,
so I've brought my wives.
You should take this opportunity
to become friends.
Tenasina, take care of the rest, won't you?
Leave it to me.
I am his first wife, Tenasina.
There is something I would like to
make clear from the very beginning.
Y-Yes?
Normally you, the daughter of a count,
would be superior to us in social standing.
But once you have married Lord Charles,
as his seventh wife, your place
amongst us is at the very bottom.
Of course. I understand.
I will not allow any impertinent behavior.
It shall be as you say.
I am inexperienced and inept,
but I hope you will look on me kindly.
Your complexion looks terrible.
You are going to be a bride of the
House of Duke Arbor, you know.
Smile more brightly.
Y-Yes.
Well, I suppose that will do.
L-Lady Celia!
What is all this noise?
Her Highness, Princess Christina,
First Princess of the Realm is here!
Princess Christina?
Let her through right away!
Yes, my lady!
Who gave you leave to—
My deepest apologies!
But would it not shame the House of Duke Arbor
to keep Princess Christina waiting?
Princess Christina!
What an honor to see you!
I am sorry for arriving
so suddenly, with no prior notice.
Please, don't trouble yourselves for me.
Thank you so much for
coming, Princess Christina!
My!
You look beautiful, Professor!
That wedding dress suits
you wonderfully well!
Th-Thank you very much.
Princess Christina, please come
inside and rest at your leisure!
I was hoping to speak with my
former teacher, Professor Celia, in private.
Oh! P-P-Please forgive my impertinence!
W-Well then, we will take our leave.
Now, ladies, let us go!
Professor, I've come to offer congratulations
in place of my mother and father.
Thank you very much.
You truly are beautiful, Professor!
I-I accept your words of praise
with a heart full of gratitude.
I'm glad.
What?
Your complexion looks a little
better than it did earlier.
O-Oh...
Did those individuals say
something unpleasant to you?
No. I was just so nervous yesterday
that I didn't sleep well.
I think that might be the cause.
I see.
It really has been a while, hasn't it?
Princess Christina, I'm so
happy to see you again!
So am I!
It's thanks to you, Professor, that I'm
finally able to be outside like this.
For so long, I had been confined in the palace.
The scrutiny of Duke Arbor's faction
is quite stringent, isn't it?
In my case, the inadequacy of the
royal family is the cause of it.
I believe Flora feels the same.
When Duke Huguenot fled
the kingdom with Princess Flora ...
I'm sure it must have been painful.
It made me see that all faith in the
power of the royal family had been lost.
And the ill effects of that have
resulted in your wedding, Professor.
I am truly sorry for all of this!
P-Princess Christina!
This wedding is something I decided upon!
Why are you apologizing?
Because I've stolen your
smile from you, Professor.
While I attended the Academy,
I admired and looked up
to you, Professor Celia.
Back then, Professor, you seemed
so clearly happy, unlike now.
Now, you're like a bird locked in a cage.
If there were ever a chance for you to
regain the smile you had back then...
Princess Christina...
I swear I will do everything in my
power to help when the time comes.
Thank you.
And I will pray that you and
Princess Flora will one day be reunited.
It looks to be a lavish ceremony.
Yes, it will be.
We should get going—
Alfred...
You are about to gloriously take command
of the assembled forces, are you not?
After all, you are the strongest
warrior in the kingdom.
Your skills have caused some
to call you the King's Sword.
But how unfortunate for you.
I have authority over the
security for the ceremony.
You have no choice but to obey my orders.
I only ever think of how
I might fulfill my bounden duty.
Well, don't go showing off.
Year one thousand of the Holy Era. Spring.
Year 1000 of the Holy Era, Spring
Thus, the wedding ceremony between
Professor Celia and Charles Arbor began.
I can't see!
Here they come!
They're nearly here!
They're crossing the bridge!
I can see them!
Here they come!
Amazing!
That's a huge procession!
Oh, it's the bride!
She's all silver...
Long live the Silver Bride!
The Silver Bride!
I see. The Silver Bride, is it?
Coming from ignorant peasants,
that's not a bad appellation.
Well, it just shows how
very beautiful you are.
Th-Thank you.
When I think that very soon you
will be mine and mine alone...
I look forward to the moment
we kiss to seal our oaths.
Long live the House of Arbor!
Long live Lord Charles Arbor!
One day, this kingdom will be mine.
And you will be wife to me.
Are they here yet?
Haruto, Celia is close.
It seems so.
Haruto, you're very calm.
It's thanks to you, Aishia.
I only investigated. It wasn't very much.
That's not true. Thanks to that,
I understand a lot more.
It's the bride!
I see them!
She's so beautiful!
Long live the bride!
Long live the Silver Bride!
Lord Charles! Lord Charles!
Professor...
Haruto, I'm going to go now.
Yes.
Celia?
Huh? What?
Celia, stay calm.
Who are you?
I'm Aishia.
Haruto—no, Rio asked me
to talk to you this way.
Rio did?
Look to your right.
Rio...
Rio!
Why are you here?
I told you not to come!
Rio, you were the one person
I didn't want to see me like this!
Hey, now! What's wrong, Celia?
Oh, I...
I'm not sure. So many feelings
suddenly welled up...
I see. You're so happy you're crying?
I didn't realize you cared for me so.
But we must be dignified here.
Everyone is watching, you see.
Yes.
Good.
Aishia, can you hear me?
Where has Rio gone?
Was it... all a fantasy?
Celia...
I am... a doll.
Halt!
Hurry!
Seize him!
There's an intruder!
Next Time
Fated Reunion
"Fated Reunion."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
Rio!
By Minazuki Futago
fwhoosh
Professor
Celia!
whoom
ziiing
Hah
pop
Meow
It's
a
kitty
Really...
You really
can use cat-
trans-
formation
magic...